(Watch on www.dramacool.club Support Admin)
(شاهد على www.dramacool.club دعم الإدارة)
[Flower-Crowned General's Mansion]
[قصر الجنرال المتوج بالزهور]
Whoa!
يا إلهي!
My Lord, we're at the General's Mansion.
يا سيدي، نحن في قصر الجنرال.
Changyu.
تشانغيو.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I miss you.
أفتقدك.
[Flower-Crowned General's Mansion]
[قصر الجنرال المتوج بالزهور]
Changyu.
تشانغيو.
Don't be like this.
لا تكن هكذا.
Calm down.
اهدأ.
His Lordship is seriously injured.
أصيب صاحب السعادة بجروح خطيرة.
Here is the plan. You guys stay here and keep watch.
إليكم الخطة. ابقوا هنا وراقبوا.
I'll go find a doctor.
سأذهب لأبحث عن طبيب.
A doctor won't help with this.
لن يفيدك الطبيب في هذا الأمر.
Why not?
ولم لا؟
Why won't a doctor help?
لماذا لا يساعد الطبيب؟
You don't understand?
ألا تفهم؟
I see.
أرى.
I'll go to the Imperial Hospital to find a royal physician.
سأذهب إلى المستشفى الإمبراطوري لأجد طبيباً ملكياً.
No need for that.
لا حاجة لذلك.
Inside there...
في الداخل هناك...
I can't explain it to you.
لا أستطيع أن أشرح لك ذلك.
You guys,
يا رفاق،
find a few sensible older maids
ابحثي عن بعض الخادمات الأكبر سناً والعاقلات
and have them stand at the four corners
واجعلهم يقفون عند الزوايا الأربع
and keep watch from a distance.
وراقب من مسافة بعيدة.
Don't let anyone get close.
لا تدع أحداً يقترب.
-Yes. -Yes, Brother.
- نعم. - نعم يا أخي.
Go.
يذهب.
What about me?
ماذا عني؟
Just don't make trouble. Come with me.
لا تُثير المشاكل. تعال معي.
But...
لكن...
I've realized something about you.
لقد أدركت شيئاً عنك.
You can't just fight wars all the time.
لا يمكنك خوض الحروب طوال الوقت.
You need to understand life a bit.
عليك أن تفهم الحياة قليلاً.
Which aspect?
أي جانب؟
♪ In a lifetime of storms, a fleeting bloom ♪
♪ في حياة مليئة بالعواصف، زهرة عابرة ♪
Calm down first.
اهدأ أولاً.
I'll get a doctor.
سأذهب إلى الطبيب.
♪ The most beautiful scenery becomes a poem ♪
♪ أجمل المناظر الطبيعية تتحول إلى قصيدة ♪
♪ For a chance encounter ♪
♪ للقاءٍ عابر ♪
♪ A single letter of longing, half a lifetime apart ♪
♪ رسالة واحدة من الشوق، تفصل بينهما نصف عمر ♪
♪ I'll burn out my passion for you ♪
سأحرق شغفي من أجلك ♪
♪ Just for a glance ♪
♪ لمحة سريعة ♪
♪ In this life ♪
♪ في هذه الحياة ♪
♪ All that I can see or hear ♪
♪ كل ما أستطيع رؤيته أو سماعه ♪
♪ Is that we'll live and die together ♪
♪ هل يعني ذلك أننا سنعيش ونموت معًا ♪
♪ On this journey ♪
♪ في هذه الرحلة ♪
♪ You're all that I care about ♪
♪ أنت كل ما يهمني ♪
♪ My soul yearns and my dreams linger ♪
♪ روحي تتوق وأحلامي تلاحقني ♪
♪ After we part ♪
♪ بعد أن نفترق ♪
♪ Where love dwells, where fear lies ♪
♪ حيث يسكن الحب، وحيث يكمن الخوف ♪
♪ Just one thought makes me sick ♪
مجرد فكرة واحدة تُشعرني بالغثيان ♪
Who am I?
من أنا؟
♪ I wish to leave this world with you ♪
♪ أتمنى أن أغادر هذا العالم معك ♪
♪ In this life ♪
♪ في هذه الحياة ♪
♪ All that I can see or hear ♪
♪ كل ما أستطيع رؤيته أو سماعه ♪
♪ Is that we'll live and die together ♪
♪ هل يعني ذلك أننا سنعيش ونموت معًا ♪
Fan Changyu.
فان تشانغيو.
♪ On this journey ♪
♪ في هذه الرحلة ♪
♪ You're all that I care about ♪
♪ أنت كل ما يهمني ♪
♪ My soul yearns and my dreams linger ♪
♪ روحي تتوق وأحلامي تلاحقني ♪
♪ After we part ♪
♪ بعد أن نفترق ♪
♪ Where love dwells, where fear lies ♪
♪ حيث يسكن الحب، وحيث يكمن الخوف ♪
♪ Just one thought makes me sick ♪
مجرد فكرة واحدة تُشعرني بالغثيان ♪
♪ I wish to leave this world with you ♪
♪ أتمنى أن أغادر هذا العالم معك ♪
♪ We'll never be apart ♪
♪ لن نفترق أبداً ♪
It seems there is no need for me to intervene.
يبدو أنه لا داعي لتدخلي .
This is even better.
هذا أفضل بكثير.
Nature takes its course.
الطبيعة تأخذ مجراها.
Royal Physician,
الطبيب الملكي،
you haven't even checked on him.
لم تتفقد حاله حتى.
Are you the royal physician,
هل أنت الطبيب الملكي؟
or am I?
أم أنني كذلك؟
I...
أنا...
I told you that you don't need a doctor for such things.
قلت لك إنك لست بحاجة إلى طبيب لمثل هذه الأمور.
And you actually invited a royal physician?
وهل قمت بدعوة طبيب ملكي بالفعل؟
It was a wasted trip.
كانت رحلة ضائعة.
Let's go, let's go.
هيا بنا، هيا بنا.
You two.
أنتما الاثنان.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
So what exactly is life?
إذن ما هي الحياة بالضبط؟
[Pursuit of Jade]
[السعي وراء اليشم]
[Episode 38]
[الحلقة 38]
The Emperor got a slap in the face?
هل تلقى الإمبراطور صفعة على وجهه؟
It was worth the fire I sent him.
كان الأمر يستحق النار التي أرسلتها إليه.
It's just a pity
إنه لأمر مؤسف حقاً
that the Marquis of Wu'an and Fan Changyu escaped.
أن ماركيز ووآن وفان تشانغيو قد هربا.
Your Li family has a traitor within.
يوجد خائن في عائلة لي الخاصة بك.
Shouldn't he be punished properly?
ألا ينبغي معاقبته بالشكل المناسب؟
My grandson
حفيدي
was bewitched by the Marquis of Wu'an and Fan Changyu for a moment
سُحرت للحظة من قبل ماركيز ووآن وفان تشانغيو
and ruined today's grand plan.
وأفسد الخطة الكبرى لليوم.
I will bear all the blame
سأتحمل كل اللوم
for him.
من أجله.
Grand Tutor, there's no need for such seriousness.
يا معلمنا الكبير، لا داعي لهذه الجدية.
In this way,
وبهذه الطريقة،
we have effectively cut off any possibility
لقد قطعنا فعلياً أي احتمال
of cooperation between the Marquis of Wu'an and Qi Sheng.
التعاون بين ماركيز ووآن وتشي شنغ.
Besides,
بجانب،
I even prepared a big gift
بل لقد أعددت هدية كبيرة
for that butcher girl.
من أجل تلك الفتاة الجزارة.
If Wei Yan knows it,
إذا كان وي يان يعلم بذلك،
he will be very happy.
سيكون سعيداً جداً.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
The Tiger Tally he has been longing for.
حصيلة النمور التي كان يتوق إليها.
The Tiger Tally
إحصاء النمور
used to mobilize troops in the Northwest back then?
هل كان يُستخدم لتعبئة القوات في الشمال الغربي آنذاك؟
This is just the appetizer.
هذا مجرد فاتح للشهية.
The main course is yet to come.
الطبق الرئيسي لم يأت بعد.
Please.
لو سمحت.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Mother.
الأم.
Look, I picked so many osmanthus flowers.
انظروا، لقد قطفت الكثير من زهور الأوسمانثوس.
Good job, Zheng.
أحسنت يا تشنغ.
Later,
لاحقاً،
let's use these to make osmanthus candy. Okay?
لنستخدم هذه الأشياء لصنع حلوى الأوسمانثوس. حسناً؟
Yay!
ياي!
Smell them.
شمّها.
Mother!
الأم!
You're here, Zheng?
أنت هنا يا تشنغ؟
Sit down. Have some osmanthus cake.
اجلس. تناول بعض كعكة الأوسمانثوس.
I finally
أخيرًا
get to see you again.
أتطلع لرؤيتك مجدداً.
Now that you have someone by your side
الآن وقد أصبح لديك شخص بجانبك
who understands and cherishes you,
من يفهمك ويعتز بك،
I can rest easy.
يمكنني أن أرتاح بالاً.
Remember…
يتذكر…
osmanthus cake
كعكة الأوسمانثوس
is my favorite.
هو المفضل لدي.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Did you have a nightmare?
هل رأيت كابوساً؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
I just had a dream about my childhood.
لقد حلمت للتو بذكريات طفولتي.
Changyu.
تشانغيو.
For you to be with me like this…
أن تكون معي هكذا...
I've treated you unfairly.
لقد عاملتك بظلم.
When I settle down,
عندما أستقر،
I will definitely give you a proper wedding.
سأقيم لكم حفل زفاف يليق بكم بكل تأكيد.
You didn't treat me unfairly.
لم تعاملني بظلم.
I am willing to marry Xie Zheng.
أنا على استعداد للزواج من شيه تشنغ.
But Yan Zheng married into my family.
لكن يان تشنغ تزوج من عائلتي.
That was also a wonderful wedding.
كان ذلك أيضاً حفل زفاف رائع.
We haven't signed the Divorce Agreement yet.
لم نوقع اتفاقية الطلاق بعد.
Don't you deny it.
لا تنكر ذلك.
I won't.
أنا لن.
I will be your matrilocal husband
سأكون زوجك في بيت زوجتك
for life.
مدى الحياة.
This trip to the Capital
هذه الرحلة إلى العاصمة
has been one trouble after another.
لقد كانت سلسلة من المشاكل المتتالية.
Now I just want to clear Father's name
الآن أريد فقط تبرئة اسم والدي
as soon as possible,
في أسرع وقت ممكن،
return to Lin'an,
العودة إلى لينآن،
and live a peaceful life.
وعيش حياة هادئة.
But regarding last night,
أما بخصوص الليلة الماضية،
I'm afraid it wasn't that simple.
أخشى أن الأمر لم يكن بهذه البساطة.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I have a plan.
لدي خطة.
[Where Compassion and Grace Meet]
[حيث تلتقي الرحمة والنعمة]
Be... be careful.
كن... كن حذراً.
Easy.
سهل.
I thought I'd never see you again.
ظننت أنني لن أراك مرة أخرى.
I thought I was going to die there.
ظننت أنني سأموت هناك.
It's alright now.
الأمور على ما يرام الآن.
I'm right here with you.
أنا هنا معك.
Don't cry.
لا تبكي.
It's alright.
لا بأس.
Last night,
ليلة أمس،
did you stay here and take care of me all night?
هل بقيت هنا واعتنيت بي طوال الليل؟
Yes.
نعم.
You haven't rested at all?
ألم تسترح على الإطلاق؟
Then how could you...
إذن كيف يمكنك...
Yesterday, to save me,
أمس، لإنقاذي،
you rushed into the fire.
اندفعت نحو النار.
I was so afraid you'd die in there.
كنت خائفًا جدًا من أن تموت هناك.
-Alright, alright. -You must be hurt.
-حسناً، حسناً. -لا بد أنك مصاب.
-Let me see. -Alright, alright.
- دعني أرى. - حسناً، حسناً.
You're very weak right now.
أنت ضعيف جداً الآن.
Stop talking.
توقف عن الكلام.
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
In the past,
في الماضي،
I was always so timid.
كنت دائمًا خجولًا جدًا.
But this time,
لكن هذه المرة،
I want to tell you,
أريد أن أخبرك،
from now on,
من الآن فصاعدًا،
no matter what happens,
بغض النظر عما يحدث،
I will stay by your side.
سأبقى بجانبك.
And only I can take care of you.
وأنا وحدي من يستطيع الاعتناء بك.
This Tiger Tally doesn't match.
هذا الإحصاء الخاص بالنمور غير متطابق.
It's fake.
إنه مزيف.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
this Tiger Tally is real.
هذا العدد من النمور حقيقي.
Crown Prince Chengde and General Xie can't hold on much longer.
لم يعد بإمكان ولي العهد تشنغده والجنرال شيه الصمود لفترة أطول.
Jinzhou is in danger!
جينتشو في خطر!
For the sake of the country and the people,
من أجل مصلحة الوطن والشعب،
please send troops to rescue them immediately!
أرجو إرسال قوات لإنقاذهم على الفور!
General.
عام.
Come in.
ادخل.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
General,
عام،
Guard Jin has been waiting outside for a long time.
كان الحارس جين ينتظر في الخارج لفترة طويلة.
He asked that you see him as soon as you wake up.
طلب منك أن تراه فور استيقاظك.
I see.
أرى.
You may go.
يمكنك الذهاب.
There is a letter here.
توجد رسالة هنا.
It's for you personally.
إنه لك شخصياً.
[To Fan Changyu]
[إلى فان تشانغيو]
[I'm fine now. Don't worry about me. Qianqian]
أنا بخير الآن. لا تقلقوا عليّ. تشيان تشيان
It's from Qianqian?
هل هي من تشيان تشيان؟
The Tiger Tally?
عدد النمور؟
Where did this come from?
من أين أتى هذا؟
Last night,
ليلة أمس،
a maid delivering a letter was found dead
تم العثور على جثة خادمة كانت تقوم بتسليم رسالة
at the gate of our General's Mansion.
عند بوابة قصر جنرالنا.
Help!
يساعد!
[Flower-Crowned General's Mansion]
[قصر الجنرال المتوج بالزهور]
Guards!
حراس!
She's dead?
هل ماتت؟
You guys, bring your weapons.
يا رفاق، أحضروا أسلحتكم.
Search around for any suspicious individuals.
ابحث في المنطقة المحيطة عن أي أفراد مشبوهين.
[Flower-Crowned General's Mansion]
[قصر الجنرال المتوج بالزهور]
Yes!
نعم!
That dream just now...
ذلك الحلم الذي رأيته للتو...
Could it be that
هل يمكن أن يكون ذلك
Heaven also wants to seek justice for my father?
هل يريد السماء أيضاً أن تسعى لتحقيق العدالة لأبي؟
General.
عام.
Someone named Lady Shisan wants to see you.
هناك سيدة تدعى السيدة شيسان تريد رؤيتك.
Lady Shisan?
السيدة شيسان؟
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك.
No need.
لا حاجة.
I want to talk to her alone.
أريد التحدث معها على انفراد.
That lowly maid has already delivered the Tiger Tally
لقد سلمت تلك الخادمة المتواضعة بالفعل إحصاء النمور
to Fan Changyu.
إلى فان تشانغيو.
Deal with it.
تعامل مع الأمر.
Yes.
نعم.
You weren't drunk that day?
ألم تكن ثملاً في ذلك اليوم؟
I love you so much.
أنا أحبك جداً.
Why did you do this to me?
لماذا فعلت بي هذا؟
Every time I think
في كل مرة أفكر
you won't leave me
لن تتركني
and that you're willing to be with me,
وأنك على استعداد لأن تكون معي،
it always ends up like this.
دائماً ما ينتهي الأمر على هذا النحو.
Is my love so cheap
هل حبي رخيص إلى هذه الدرجة؟
that you can just trample on it?
هل يمكنك ببساطة أن تدوس عليه؟
That isn't love.
هذا ليس حباً.
It's possessiveness!
إنها غريزة التملك!
It's a desire for control!
إنها رغبة في السيطرة!
I am about to become the Emperor.
أنا على وشك أن أصبح الإمبراطور.
Without me,
بدوني،
you won't be an empress.
لن تصبحي إمبراطورة.
You are nothing.
أنت لا شيء.
I don't care about being an empress.
لا يهمني أن أصبح إمبراطورة.
Without you,
بدونك،
I will live a better life.
سأعيش حياة أفضل.
Kill me if you have the guts.
اقتلني إن كنت تملك الشجاعة.
Are you alright? Are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟ هل أنت بخير؟
I... I'm begging you.
أنا... أنا أتوسل إليك.
Please tell me—
أرجوك أخبرني—
as long as you don't leave me,
طالما أنك لن تتركني،
whatever you want,
أياً كان ما تريد،
I will give it to you!
سأعطيك إياه!
I don't want anything.
لا أريد شيئاً.
I just want to leave you forever.
أريد فقط أن أتركك إلى الأبد.
You forced me to do this.
لقد أجبرتني على فعل هذا.
Bring the shackles!
أحضروا الأغلال!
Yes.
نعم.
These are cast from refined steel.
هذه مصنوعة من الفولاذ المكرر.
Even blades and axes cannot break them.
حتى الشفرات والفؤوس لا تستطيع كسرها.
If you want to escape,
إذا كنت ترغب في الهروب،
you must cut off one of our hands.
يجب عليك قطع إحدى أيدينا.
You're crazy.
أنت مجنون.
You must have lost your mind!
لا بد أنك فقدت عقلك!
You can't escape.
لا يمكنك الهروب.
In this lifetime,
في هذه الحياة،
you belong only to me.
أنتِ ملكي وحدي.
I didn't expect you to be alive.
لم أتوقع أن تكون على قيد الحياة.
Why do you want to see me?
لماذا تريد رؤيتي؟
To avenge Sui Yuanqing?
للانتقام من Sui Yuanqing؟
It seems that
يبدو أن
I'm the only one left who still remembers to avenge him.
أنا الوحيد المتبقي الذي ما زال يتذكر أن ينتقم له.
This is for you.
هذا لك.
Sui Yuanqing gave it to me.
أعطاها لي Sui Yuanqing.
And this.
وهذا أيضاً.
I'm leaving you a way out.
سأترك لك مخرجاً.
Take this and go find Fan Changyu,
خذ هذا واذهب للبحث عن فان تشانغيو،
and I will give you a...
وسأعطيك...
token of loyalty.
رمز للولاء.
The Tiger Tally is yours.
إحصاء النمور من نصيبك.
And he is dead.
وقد مات.
I guess
اعتقد
he just wanted Qi Min
كان يريد فقط تشي مين
to be doomed eternally.
أن يُحكم عليه بالهلاك الأبدي.
What about you?
ماذا عنك؟
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
Me?
أنا؟
I used to think
كنت أعتقد
you and Xie Zheng were my enemies.
أنت وشيه تشنغ كنتما عدويّ.
You killed my brothers.
لقد قتلت إخوتي.
And Xie Zheng wiped out my Qingfeng Stronghold.
وقد قضى شيه تشنغ على معقل تشينغفنغ الخاص بي.
Later, I felt that
لاحقاً، شعرت أن
he played with my feelings,
لقد تلاعب بمشاعري،
causing me and Qingfeng Stronghold
مما تسبب في إصابتي أنا ومعقل تشينغفنغ
to fall into ruin.
أن تنهار وتتحول إلى خراب.
But today I realized,
لكنني أدركت اليوم،
worldly grievances are born of cause and effect.
تنشأ المظالم الدنيوية من السبب والنتيجة.
Revenge is endless.
الانتقام لا ينتهي.
And all this killing
وكل هذا القتل
is never-ending too.
وهي لا تنتهي أبداً أيضاً.
I've given you the Tiger Tally.
لقد أعطيتك إحصائية النمور.
It...
هو - هي...
Take the head with you.
خذ الرأس معك.
I don't need it anymore.
لم أعد بحاجة إليه.
You can leave his body intact.
يمكنك ترك جثته سليمة.
Thank you for today.
شكراً لكم على هذا اليوم.
I'll have someone get you a new travel permit.
سأطلب من شخص ما أن يحصل لك على تصريح سفر جديد.
You'll be free from now on.
ستكون حراً من الآن فصاعداً.
Consider it repayment
اعتبرها سداداً للجميل
for your kindness to Changning.
شكراً لكرمك تجاه تشانغنينغ.
But as for the score between us,
أما بالنسبة للنتيجة بيننا،
we'll settle it when I return.
سنحسم الأمر عندما أعود.
I hope the next time we meet,
أتمنى أن نلتقي في المرة القادمة،
you're still alive.
ما زلت على قيد الحياة.
[Talisman of Army]
[تميمة الجيش]
Qianqian sent this.
أرسلت تشيان تشيان هذا.
I dreamed of Father last night.
حلمت بالأب الليلة الماضية.
I woke up to see this Tiger Tally.
استيقظت لأرى هذا العدد من النمور.
But I don't understand why
لكنني لا أفهم لماذا
Lord Changxin framed my father.
قام اللورد تشانغشين بتلفيق التهمة لوالدي.
Why should the defeat at Jinzhou
لماذا ينبغي اعتبار الهزيمة في جينتشو
and the deaths of hundreds of thousands of soldiers
ومقتل مئات الآلاف من الجنود
all be blamed on my father?
هل يُلقى اللوم كله على والدي؟
My parents had been living in anonymity for over a decade.
كان والداي يعيشان في الخفاء لأكثر من عقد من الزمان.
Why...
لماذا...
why were they still killed?
لماذا قُتلوا رغم ذلك؟
I want to clear my father's name before the world.
أريد تبرئة اسم والدي أمام العالم.
Your father
والدك
and the soldiers of Jinzhou who died in vain
وجنود جينتشو الذين ماتوا عبثاً
all deserve justice.
الجميع يستحقون العدالة.
But right now,
لكن في الوقت الراهن،
this pair of Tiger Tallies alone
هذا الزوج من علامات النمر وحده
is not enough to prove
لا يكفي لإثبات
that Wei Yan was the mastermind.
أن وي يان كان العقل المدبر.
The mad palace maid who knew the truth
خادمة القصر المجنونة التي عرفت الحقيقة
has already died in the fire.
لقد توفي بالفعل في الحريق.
There's nothing left in Qingyuan Palace.
لم يتبق شيء في قصر تشينغ يوان.
Everyone involved in this matter
كل من له صلة بهذا الأمر
has been silenced by Wei Yan.
تم إسكاته بواسطة وي يان.
The mad maid's former mistress was Consort Virtue.
كانت عشيقة الخادمة المجنونة السابقة هي كونسورت فيرتو.
What is the relationship between Consort Virtue and Wei Yan?
ما هي العلاقة بين كونسورت فيرتو ووي يان؟
It's rumored in the palace that they had an affair.
يشاع في القصر أنهما كانا على علاقة غرامية.
Then what exactly happened back then?
إذن ما الذي حدث بالضبط في ذلك الوقت؟
Are there no clues left at all?
هل لم يتبق أي دليل على الإطلاق؟
That Qi Sheng...
ذلك تشي شنغ...
Could he know something?
هل يمكن أن يكون على علم بشيء ما؟
Don't be anxious.
لا تقلق.
Even if Qi Sheng knows something,
حتى لو كان تشي شنغ يعلم شيئاً،
he wouldn't dare to say it.
لن يجرؤ على قول ذلك.
He has been a puppet for decades.
لقد كان مجرد دمية لعقود.
He is terrified of Wei Yan.
إنه مرعوب من وي يان.
He certainly wouldn't dare to pursue this.
من المؤكد أنه لن يجرؤ على متابعة هذا الأمر.
Now,
الآن،
if we want to take down Wei Yan
إذا أردنا إسقاط وي يان
and make him confess,
وأجبره على الاعتراف،
we can only use force.
لا يمكننا إلا استخدام القوة.
I called him Uncle for over 20 years.
كنت أناديه "عمي" لأكثر من 20 عامًا.
I know his nature all too well.
أعرف طبيعته جيداً.
I'm afraid
أخشى
he has already started a rebellion.
لقد بدأ بالفعل تمرداً.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I will gather all the main forces of the Xie Army
سأجمع كل القوات الرئيسية لجيش شي
to seek justice
السعي لتحقيق العدالة
for your father and mine.
من أجل والدك ووالدي.
So it has come to this, after all.
إذن، فقد وصلنا إلى هذا الحد في نهاية المطاف.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
we will act ahead of schedule.
سنتخذ الإجراءات قبل الموعد المحدد.
Pass my order.
نفذوا طلبي.
Deploy the troops back to the Capital immediately.
انشر القوات إلى العاصمة فوراً.
Yes!
نعم!
At my command!
بأمري!
Spread the news that Fan Changyu
انشروا خبر أن فان تشانغيو
is the daughter of the traitor Wei Qilin!
إنها ابنة الخائن وي كيلين!
As soon as possible!
في أسرع وقت ممكن!
Yes!
نعم!
[Graceful and Ethereal]
[رشيق وشفاف]
Flower-Crowned General.
جنرال متوج بالزهور.
by regulation, anyone who wants to beat the Petition Drum
بموجب اللوائح، يحق لأي شخص يرغب في قرع طبول العريضة
without authorization must first be paraded through the streets
يجب أولاً عرضهم في الشوارع دون تصريح
and subjected to public censure,
وتعرض للانتقاد العلني،
only then may they strike the drum to present their grievance.
عندها فقط يمكنهم قرع الطبول لعرض مظلمتهم.
[In Memory of Wan, My Late Mother, Xie Linshan's Wife]
[في ذكرى وان، والدتي الراحلة، زوجة شي لينشان]
[In Memory of My Late Father, Xie Linshan]
[في ذكرى والدي الراحل، شي لينشان]
[Guo's Wine House]
[بيت نبيذ غو]
It's her!
إنها هي!
Everyone, come and look!
هيا يا جماعة، تعالوا وانظروا!
She is the daughter of the big traitor!
إنها ابنة الخائن الكبير!
None of you in the Wei family are any good!
لا أحد منكم في عائلة وي جيد!
My father died in battle in Jinzhou!
توفي والدي في معركة في جينتشو!
Make her pay with her life!
اجعلوها تدفع حياتها ثمناً لذلك!
What nonsense are you talking about?
ما هذا الهراء الذي تتحدث عنه؟
You are spouting filth!
أنت تتفوه بالقذارة!
Do you have proof?
هل لديك دليل؟
Don't talk nonsense!
لا تتفوه بالهراء!
My sister is innocent!
أختي بريئة!
[In Memory of Wan, My Late Mother, Xie Linshan's Wife]
[في ذكرى وان، والدتي الراحلة، زوجة شي لينشان]
Father.
أب.
[In Memory of My Late Father, Xie Linshan]
[في ذكرى والدي الراحل، شي لينشان]
Mother.
الأم.
I've been an unfilial child.
لقد كنتُ ابناً عاقاً.
I pray your spirits in Heaven
أدعو الله أن يرحم أرواحكم في الجنة
will forgive me.
ستسامحني.
Beat her!
اهزمها!
Beat her to death!
اضربها حتى الموت!
If you keep spouting nonsense, I'll tear your mouths apart!
إذا استمررتم في التلفظ بالهراء، فسأمزق أفواهكم إرباً!
The big traitor,
الخائن الكبير،
Wei Qilin.
وي تشيلين.
He escorted the grain
رافق الحبوب
with no loyalty
بدون ولاء
and cost 100,000 heroes their lives!
وكلّف ذلك 100 ألف بطل حياتهم!
Hit her!
اضربها!
Kill her!
اقتلها!
Beat her!
اهزمها!
Beat her to death!
اضربها حتى الموت!
Sister!
أخت!
Fan!
معجب!
How can someone like her be a general?
كيف يمكن لشخص مثلها أن يكون جنرالاً؟
Who threw it?
من الذي رماها؟
-Who threw it?
- من رماها؟
-Good job! -Well done!
- عمل جيد! - أحسنت!
Good job!
أحسنت!
-Will you ever stop? -You want to get physical?
- هل ستتوقف يوماً ما؟ - هل تريد أن تمارس الجنس؟
Stop!
قف!
My father is Wei Qilin.
والدي هو وي كيلين.
But he is not a traitor.
لكنه ليس خائناً.
He was wrongly accused.
لقد اتُهم ظلماً.
-That's your father! -Your father caused their death!
- هذا والدك! - والدك هو من تسبب في موتهم!
Of course you'd say he's innocent!
بالطبع ستقول إنه بريء!
Exactly!
بالضبط!
Hit her!
اضربها!
Enough is enough!
كفى!
Back off! All of you, back off!
ابتعدوا! جميعكم، ابتعدوا!
Kill her!
اقتلها!
Officials are handling the case!
يتولى المسؤولون القضية!
Bystanders, stand back!
أيها المارة، تراجعوا!
Back off!
ابتعد!
Step back!
تراجع للخلف!
Move back!
تراجع!
Are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
Nonsense!
هراء!
Flower-Crowned General?
جنرال متوج بالزهور؟
More like Traitor General!
بل هو أقرب إلى الجنرال الخائن!
Shut up!
اسكت!
Did any of you see it with your own eyes?
هل رأى أحدكم ذلك بأم عينيه؟
Are you sure what you heard and saw
هل أنت متأكد مما سمعت ورأيت؟
is the truth?
هل هذه هي الحقيقة؟
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك.
We'll go with you too.
سنذهب معك أيضاً.
The rest of the way,
أما بقية الطريق،
I'll walk alone.
سأسير وحدي.
Once you take this step,
بمجرد اتخاذك لهذه الخطوة،
there's no turning back.
لا رجعة إلى الوراء.
Let me go.
دعني أذهب.
Let her go.
اسمح لها أن تذهب.
I'm Fan Changyu from Xigu Lane,
أنا فان تشانغيو من Xigu Lane.
Lin'an Town, Qingping County.
مدينة لينان، مقاطعة تشينغ بينغ.
I have come
لقد أتيت
to file an imperial appeal.
لتقديم استئناف إمبراطوري.
Those who file an imperial appeal,
أولئك الذين يقدمون استئنافاً إمبراطورياً،
if the accusations are false,
إذا كانت الاتهامات كاذبة،
commit the crime of deceiving the Sovereign.
ارتكاب جريمة خداع الملك.
The penalty is immediate beheading.
العقوبة هي قطع الرأس فوراً.
Have you thought this through?
هل فكرت في هذا الأمر جيداً؟
I have.
أملك.
This trip is,
هذه الرحلة هي،
first, to denounce the injustice of Heaven.
أولاً، التنديد بظلم السماء.
[Yin]
[يفعل]
Wei Qilin,
وي تشيلين,
you are a traitor, worse than a beast!
أنت خائن، أسوأ من الوحش!
[Wei Qilin, Traitor of Great Yin]
[وي تشيلين، خائن يين العظيم]
♪ The world is vast ♪
♪ العالم واسع ♪
-Traitor -Traitor Wei!
-خائن -خائن واي!
Traitor Wei!
خائن وي!
[Wei Qilin]
[وي تشيلين]
Beat him!
اهزمه!
Second, to accuse the Emperor of ignorance!
ثانياً، اتهام الإمبراطور بالجهل!
♪ The storm is rising ♪
♪ العاصفة تتصاعد ♪
[Think with Caution]
[فكر بحذر]
Who's beating the drum?
من الذي يقرع الطبول؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
It's the Flower-Crowned General beating the Petition Drum.
إنه الجنرال المتوج بالزهور وهو يقرع طبول العريضة.
♪ Day and night ♪
♪ ليلاً ونهاراً ♪
She says she wants to file an imperial appeal.
وتقول إنها تريد تقديم استئناف إمبراطوري.
♪ We strive to save the world ♪
♪ نسعى جاهدين لإنقاذ العالم ♪
Didn't Grand Tutor Li say
ألم يقل المعلم الكبير لي
we could use Xie Zheng and Fan Changyu to deal with Wei Yan?
هل يمكننا استخدام Xie Zheng وFan Changyu للتعامل مع Wei Yan؟
Deal with him, my ass!
هراء، سأتعامل معه!
She is beating the Petition Drum!
إنها تدق طبول العريضة!
♪ All people ♪
♪ جميع الناس ♪
And third,
وثالثًا،
to indict the treacherous ministers in power!
لمحاسبة الوزراء الخونة في السلطة!
♪ Are part of the past ♪
♪ جزء من الماضي ♪
I, Fan Changyu,
أنا، فان تشانغيو،
am here today to clear my father's name!
أنا هنا اليوم لأبرئ ساحة والدي!
♪ What's the date today? ♪
♪ ما هو تاريخ اليوم؟ ♪
♪ How lamentable ♪
♪ يا للأسف ♪
Zheng,
تشنغ،
I made these osmanthus cakes myself.
لقد صنعت كعكات الأوسمانثوس هذه بنفسي.
Remember,
يتذكر،
what I love most
أكثر ما أحبه
is this osmanthus cake.
هل هذه كعكة الأوسمانثوس؟
Yan, when you read this, it's like seeing me.
يان، عندما تقرأ هذا، ستشعر وكأنك تراني.
When you return in triumph and read this,
عندما تعود منتصراً وتقرأ هذا،
I will likely have passed away.
من المحتمل أنني سأكون قد فارقت الحياة.
I only wish that in the next life,
أتمنى فقط أن يحدث ذلك في الحياة الأخرى،
you will be a commoner,
ستصبح شخصاً عادياً،
and I will be by your side forever.
وسأبقى بجانبك إلى الأبد.
Rongyin's final letter.
رسالة رونغين الأخيرة.
It was actually Brother
كان في الواقع الأخ
who returned to the Capital halfway,
الذين عادوا إلى العاصمة في منتصف الطريق،
causing the fall of Jinzhou.
مما تسبب في سقوط جينتشو.
So Linshan's death
موت لينشان
was also caused by him.
وقد تسبب هو أيضاً في ذلك.
Zheng.
تشنغ.
The situation is unstable now.
الوضع غير مستقر الآن.
[In Memory of Wan, My Late Mother, Xie Linshan's Wife]
[في ذكرى وان، والدتي الراحلة، زوجة شي لينشان]
The soldiers of the Xie Army are threatening
جنود جيش شيه يهددون
[In Memory of My Late Father, Xie Linshan]
[في ذكرى والدي الراحل، شي لينشان]
my brother with their lives to make him reveal the truth of the Jinzhou case.
أخي يخاطر بحياته ليجعله يكشف حقيقة قضية جينتشو.
I'm caught in the middle, unable to make my own choices.
أنا عالق في المنتصف، غير قادر على اتخاذ قراراتي الخاصة.
Perhaps only my death
ربما موتي فقط
can settle this dispute.
يمكن تسوية هذا النزاع.
I hope this will also awaken my brother's conscience
آمل أن يوقظ هذا ضمير أخي أيضاً
and have him give you a chance to live.
واجعله يمنحك فرصة للعيش.
Zheng,
تشنغ،
do not miss me.
لا تشتاق إليّ.
I can't be with you as you grow up.
لا أستطيع أن أكون معك وأنت تكبر.
Mother.
الأم.
I'm unfilial.
أنا عاقّ.
It took me so long
استغرق الأمر مني وقتاً طويلاً
to understand your good intentions.
لفهم نواياك الحسنة.
[Wei Residence]
[سكن وي]
Stop beating the drum!
توقف عن قرع الطبول!
The Princess Royal is here!
الأميرة الملكية هنا!
Brother!
أخ!
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
Sister?
أخت؟
I know what you want to say.
أعرف ما تريد قوله.
But this is not the time
لكن هذا ليس الوقت المناسب
to talk about your friendship with her.
للتحدث عن صداقتك معها.
Once the Petition Drum is struck,
بمجرد قرع طبلة العريضة،
the Emperor must hold court
يجب على الإمبراطور أن يعقد بلاطه
to hear the subjects' pleas or grievances!
للاستماع إلى مناشدات أو شكاوى الأشخاص المعنيين!
Changyu's grievance
شكوى تشانغيو
has been blown out of proportion by those with ulterior motives.
تم تضخيم الأمر بشكل مبالغ فيه من قبل أولئك الذين لديهم دوافع خفية.
The whole world knows about it now.
العالم كله يعرف ذلك الآن.
Brother, you can't hide from this.
يا أخي، لا يمكنك الاختباء من هذا.
Brother!
أخ!
You framed Xie Zheng
لقد قمت بتأطير شيه تشنغ
and nearly cost me my life.
وكاد ذلك أن يكلفني حياتي.
I haven't settled this score with you yet.
لم أحسم هذا الأمر معك بعد.
But if you can show the authority of an emperor
لكن إذا استطعت إظهار سلطة الإمبراطور
and clear Changyu's name,
وتبرئة اسم تشانغيو،
I will wipe the slate clean.
سأبدأ صفحة جديدة.
Brother!
أخ!
One must respect oneself to be respected.
يجب على المرء أن يحترم نفسه ليحظى بالاحترام.
Show the bearing of a true ruler!
أظهر سلوك حاكم حقيقي!
Do you want to be a puppet emperor forever?
هل تريد أن تبقى إمبراطوراً دمية إلى الأبد؟
Servants!
أيها الخدم!
Summon Fan Changyu for an audience.
استدعِ فان تشانغيو للحضور.
Proceed to Chongde Hall.
توجه إلى قاعة تشونغدي.
I am going to exercise the authority of the Emperor.
سأمارس سلطة الإمبراطور.
[Chongde Hall]
[قاعة تشونغدي]
Regarding the unjust case of Jinzhou 17 years ago,
فيما يتعلق بقضية جينتشو الظالمة قبل 17 عاماً،
Wei Qilin was framed.
تم تأطير وي تشيلين.
Today, I, Fan Changyu, stake my life
اليوم، أنا، فان تشانغيو، أراهن بحياتي
to implore Your Majesty
أناشد جلالتكم
to uphold justice
لإرساء العدالة
and right the wrongs!
وتصحيح الأخطاء!
This is the Tiger Tally
هذا هو إحصاء النمور
Wei Qilin used to seek help in Chongzhou.
اعتاد وي تشيلين طلب المساعدة في تشونغتشو.
This is the truth.
هذه هي الحقيقة.
But back then, Lord Changxin
لكن في ذلك الوقت، كان اللورد تشانغشين
claimed this Tiger Tally was a fake
زعموا أن هذا العدد من إحصائيات النمور مزيف
and refused to send troops.
ورفض إرسال قوات.
That is what caused the Jinzhou Massacre.
هذا ما تسبب في مذبحة جينتشو.
It shows
هذا واضح
that someone deliberately delayed military action.
أن أحدهم تعمد تأخير العمل العسكري.
The Xie and Wei families
عائلتا شي ووي
were both framed.
تم تأطير كليهما.
If this is proven true,
إذا ثبتت صحة ذلك،
Fan,
معجب،
how do you wish for me to punish the culprit?
كيف ترغب أن أعاقب الجاني؟
This is a fake.
هذا مزيف.
Shameless.
وقح.
On what grounds do you call it fake?
على أي أساس تعتبره مزيفاً؟
On what grounds?
على أي أساس؟
On the grounds that among those present,
على أساس أن من بين الحاضرين،
the only one who was there during the massacre
الشخص الوحيد الذي كان موجودًا أثناء المذبحة
was me.
كنت أنا.
You claim this is real,
تزعم أن هذا حقيقي،
but what proof do you have?
لكن ما الدليل الذي لديك؟
Although I am a new general,
على الرغم من أنني جنرال جديد،
I know that
وأنا أعلم ذلك
all Tiger Tallies must be archived
يجب أرشفة جميع إحصائيات النمور
with imprints as proof.
مع وجود آثار كدليل.
We can compare them.
يمكننا مقارنتهما.
All paper records
جميع السجلات الورقية
were destroyed in the fire 17 years ago.
دُمرت في الحريق قبل 17 عامًا.
How could it be such a coincidence?
كيف يمكن أن يكون هذا محض صدفة؟
It is just that coincidental.
إنها مجرد مصادفة.
I also know
أعرف أيضاً
why you are so obsessed with this.
لماذا أنت مهووس بهذا الأمر إلى هذا الحد؟
It's simply because
ذلك ببساطة لأن
of your own selfish motives.
بدوافعك الأنانية.
[To the Prime Minister]
[إلى رئيس الوزراء]
This is...
هذا هو...
a handwritten letter from He Jingyuan.
رسالة مكتوبة بخط اليد من هي جينغ يوان.
It reveals this girl's true identity.
يكشف ذلك عن هوية هذه الفتاة الحقيقية.
Your Majesty, please take a look.
جلالتكم، تفضلوا بالاطلاع.
Wei Qilin deserted the battle back then
فرّ وي تشيلين من المعركة آنذاك
and died a violent death.
ومات ميتة عنيفة.
The only one who slipped through the net
الشخص الوحيد الذي أفلت من الشباك
is you,
أنت هو،
Wei Qilin's daughter, Wei Changyu.
ابنة وي تشيلين، وي تشانغيو.
Wei Yan!
وي يان!
Stop twisting the facts!
توقفوا عن تحريف الحقائق!
I, Fan Changyu, have a clear conscience!
أنا، فان تشانغيو، ضميري مرتاح!
Wei Changyu
وي تشانغيو
escaped the law back then.
لقد أفلتوا من القانون آنذاك.
And now she has come to court to mislead the public
والآن لجأت إلى المحكمة لتضليل الرأي العام
and attempt to destabilize Great Yin.
ومحاولة زعزعة استقرار الين العظيم.
Her intentions are worthy of execution!
نواياها تستحق التنفيذ!
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
today, I am going to impeach this evil remnant of the Wei family.
اليوم، سأقوم بعزل هذه البقية الشريرة من عائلة وي.
She should be sentenced to death
يجب الحكم عليها بالإعدام
to honor the spirits
تكريماً للأرواح
of the 100,000 soldiers who perished at Jinzhou.
من بين 100 ألف جندي لقوا حتفهم في جينتشو.
Who is the real evil remnant?
من هم البقية الشريرة الحقيقية؟
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
My Lords!
يا سادتي!
If my father truly were a villain,
لو كان والدي شريراً حقاً،
then why would Prime Minister Wei's trusted aide, General He Jingyuan,
فلماذا إذن سيفعل مساعد رئيس الوزراء وي الموثوق به، الجنرال هي جينغ يوان،
[Diligent and Virtuous]
[مجتهد وفاضل]
exchange letters with him
تبادل الرسائل معه
and want to protect the lives of my sister and me?
وأريد حماية حياتي وحياة أختي؟
I would like to ask Prime Minister Wei a question.
أود أن أطرح سؤالاً على رئيس الوزراء وي.
If my father
إذا كان والدي
were ever to become a big traitor,
لو أصبح خائناً كبيراً،
who would be the one to benefit in the end?
من سيكون المستفيد في النهاية؟
Who would?
من سيفعل ذلك؟
[Diligent and Virtuous]
[مجتهد وفاضل]
General Fan is right.
كلام الجنرال فان صحيح.
I would also like to ask,
أود أيضاً أن أسأل،
regarding the case back then,
فيما يتعلق بالقضية آنذاك،
who benefited the most?
من استفاد أكثر؟
Your Majesty, I heard you intend
جلالة الملك، سمعت أنك تنوي
to retry the case of the Jinzhou tragedy from 17 years ago.
إعادة محاكمة قضية مأساة جينتشو التي وقعت قبل 17 عاماً.
This case involves my father, Xie Linshan,
تتعلق هذه القضية بوالدي، شي لينشان.
Crown Prince Chengde,
ولي العهد تشنغده،
and 100,000 heroic souls.
و100 ألف روح بطولية.
If the investigation is to be reopened,
إذا تقرر إعادة فتح التحقيق،
how can I be absent?
كيف يمكنني أن أغيب؟
Neither your national grudge nor your family grudge
لا ضغينة وطنية ولا ضغينة عائلية
has been avenged yet.
لم يتم الانتقام بعد.
But today,
لكن اليوم،
you're actually asking for rewards for this traitor's daughter.
أنت في الواقع تطلب مكافآت لابنة هذا الخائن.
The case of the palace burning has yet to be resolved,
لم يتم حل قضية حرق القصر بعد.
and yet you are here defending her.
ومع ذلك فأنت هنا تدافع عنها.
Could it be that you,
هل يمكن أن تكون أنت،
too, harbor thoughts of rebellion?
هل تراودك أفكار التمرد أيضاً؟
I'm afraid the one
أخشى أن يكون هو الشخص الوحيد
with thoughts of rebellion is someone else.
شخص آخر لديه أفكار التمرد .
This letter
هذه الرسالة
is a plea for help written by Consort Virtue to Wei Yan back then.
هي نداء استغاثة كتبته كونسورت فيرتو إلى وي يان في ذلك الوقت.
Wei Yan, for his own private affection,
وي يان، من أجل عاطفته الخاصة،
returned to the Capital unauthorized,
عاد إلى العاصمة دون إذن،
abandoning the soldiers of Jinzhou at the front line,
التخلي عن جنود جينتشو على خط المواجهة،
eventually
مؤخراً
causing a great disaster.
مما يتسبب في كارثة عظيمة.
[Yan, I hope this letter finds you well. Disaster has struck suddenly.]
[يان، أتمنى أن تصلك هذه الرسالة وأنت بخير. لقد حلت كارثة فجأة.]
[I can only hope you]
[لا يسعني إلا أن آمل ذلك]
[will aid me in this time of peril.]
[سيساعدني في هذا الوقت العصيب.]
[The Beijue tribes have invaded Great Yin, and my father has led the army]
[غزت قبائل بيجوي يين العظمى، وقاد والدي الجيش]
[to resist them. We thought this would ensure the safety of the country,]
[لمقاومتهم. كنا نعتقد أن هذا سيضمن سلامة البلاد]
[but it turned out to be a dark scheme]
[لكن اتضح أنها مؤامرة خبيثة]
[of treacherous men. That foolish ruler trusted slander too readily.]
[من الرجال الخونة. ذلك الحاكم الأحمق وثق بالافتراءات بسهولة بالغة.]
It's a case of the guilty accusing the innocent.
إنها حالة اتهام المذنب للبريء.
Wei Yan,
وي يان,
you are the biggest traitor in the Battle of Jinzhou!
أنت أكبر خائن في معركة جينتشو!
[Great Yin Gate]
[بوابة يين العظيمة]
[Yin]
[يفعل]
We have our people within the Imperial Guard.
لدينا رجالنا داخل الحرس الإمبراطوري.
The palace gates will fall without an attack.
ستسقط أبواب القصر دون أي هجوم.
I have already spread the news from the Imperial Astronomical Bureau.
لقد نشرتُ الخبر بالفعل من المكتب الفلكي الإمبراطوري.
The droughts and floods over these years
الجفاف والفيضانات على مدى هذه السنوات
are all due to a disruption in the imperial bloodline
كل ذلك يعود إلى خلل في السلالة الإمبراطورية
and an illegitimate succession.
وخلافة غير شرعية.
Your Highness, you're the descendant of Crown Prince Chengde.
صاحب السمو، أنت من سلالة ولي العهد تشنغده.
Your succession is the will of the people
إن خلافتك هي إرادة الشعب
and the desire of the officials.
ورغبة المسؤولين.
Good.
جيد.
It has been 17 years.
لقد مرّت 17 سنة.
I have finally returned to this place.
لقد عدت أخيراً إلى هذا المكان.